Tomasz Klosinski

DevOps / System Engineer

+33 755 77 37 37

tomasz.klosinski@protonmail.ch

For detailed list of projects visit: linkedin.com/in/tklosinski

I am passionate Linux Engineer with 4 years experience in server automation and configuration management. My current position is System Engineer in DevOps and Infrastructure teams at CERN Control Center.

Competencies

- # Linux, Bash
- # Ansible, Python,
- # Docker, Vagrant, Jenkins
- # Cloudera Hadoop
- # OpenStack, Amazon Web Services
- # Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana

Areas of Interest

- # Continuous Integration/Delivery
- # Big Data, Cloud Computing, IT Infrastructure
- # Agile Methodologies

Education

2010-2012

Polish-Japanese Academy of Information Technology Databases, M.A.

2008–2011 University of Lodz

Business Management, B.A.

2007–2010 University of Lodz Computer Science, B.A.

Cerification

- Red Hat Certified Engineer
- Red Hat Certified System Administrator

Languages

- Polish (Native)
- English (C1)
- French (A2)

Experience

04/2015-Present

CERN (Geneva)

System Engineer

- (1) System Administration Modernisation
 - Support and troubleshooting of over 2000 OpenStack VMs, desktops and servers critical to the operation of CERN accelerators.
 - Transformation of an old bash/awk/Python script-based configuration management to a modern Ansible-based solution.
 - Replacement of inconsistent/non-existing version controlling of various parts of system configuration with a single git tree.
 - Massive analysis, comparison, fixing errors and making more consistent of kickstart files for 2000+ machines (included also changes in PXE servers and generating kickstart files based on Ansible inventory file and CERN's internal sources of data about hosts).
 - Implementing a filesystem monitoring system based on auditd, rsyslog, Elasticsearch, Logstash/Logalike and Kibana (dashboards).
 - Creating monit configuration for process management and monitoring.
 - Developing dozens of Ansible playbooks for configuration of various aspects of OS and applications.

(2) Process Management and Deployment (PoC)

- Design and implementation of the platform that could replace the former legacy service management solution, while keeping the interface and release-deploy-configure workflow for users backward compatible.
- Development of Python and Ansible-based tool for:
 - deployment of the accelerators controls applications;
 - adding/removing the services to/from an applications database (to make them persistent across OS reinstallations):
 - generating configuration for service monitoring and management (based on monit);
 - providing a consistent solution for supplying user specific (monit) checks for a service or group of services.

(3) Accelerator Project Exploitation Tools - Tracing

- System administration of Elasticsearch/Logalike/Kibana clusters:
 - upgrade to ES 2.0 and Kibana 4;
 - creation of nginx reverse proxy configuration;
 - creation of monit configuration and checks for all ELK services;
 - writing a Logalike extension in Java 8.

02/2014-03/2015

LINUX POLSKA (Warsaw)

Solution Architect

(1) Open Source Day

· Organization of the biggest Open Source event in Poland.

(2) EuroLinux

- Design and implementation of Automated Delivery Pipeline for building RPM packages (using bash scripts chained into Jenkins' jobs):
 - building RPM packages with open source tools (from Fedora Project): koji, mock, mash/createrepo, revisor/pungi, Sigul;
 - maintenance and configuration of Jenkins, GitLab, git repositories, etc;
 - development of bash and Python scripts;
 - configuration of testing environment based on Vagrant, Packer, RHEV's virtual machines;
 - set up of Zabbix monitoring.

11/2011-01/2014

IMPAQ GROUP (Warsaw)

Software / System Engineer

- Support of RHEL/Oracle/Java telco applications for international cellular networks.
- Installation of a OpenStack cluster integrated with a GlusterFS cluster (automated with Chef).
- Development of Chef cookbooks for automatic orchestration of development and testing environments of Java web applications (+Apache Tomcat and Oracle XE 11g).
- Installation, configuration (using Chef) and maintenance of the Hadoop cluster and additional tools.
- Marketing and pre-sales activities for M2M, Cloud Computing and Big Data Business Practice.
- Design and implementation of the Linux services infrastructure in mVoip project:
 - load balancing and HA mode: HAProxy and nginx;
 - MySQL Master-Master Semisynchronous Replication cluster and Apache Cassandra cluster.
 - Zabbix monitoring and syslog-ng centrallized logging;
 - Jira OnDemand administration